I am yours and you are mine.
Equus is a drama, mystery, thriller film directed by Sidney Lumet.
A psychiatrist, Martin Dysart, investigates the savage blinding of six
horses with a metal spike in a stable in Hampshire, England.
The atrocity was committed by an unassuming seventeen-year-old stable boy named Alan Strang, the
only son of an opinionated but inwardly-timid father and a genteel, religious mother.
As Dysart exposes the truths behind the boy's demons, he
finds himself face-to-face with his own.
Martin Dysart, played by Richard Burton.
Alan Strang, played by Peter Firth.
Dora Strang, played by Joan Plowright.
Harry Dalton, played by Harry Andrews.
Frank Strang, played by Colin Blakely.
Hesther Saloman, played by Eileen Atkins.
Equus is a 1977 psychological drama film directed by Sidney Lumet and written
by Peter Shaffer, based on his 1973 play of the same name.
The film stars Richard Burton, Peter Firth, Colin Blakely, Joan Plowright,
Harry Andrews, Eileen Atkins, Kate Reid and Jenny Agutter.
The story concerns a psychiatrist treating a teenager who has blinded horses
in a stable, attempting to find the root of his horse worship.
Lumet's adaptation of the acclaimed play to film incorporated realism through the use of real horses
rather than human actors and provided a graphic depiction of the blinding incident.
Despite some criticism regarding this approach, the film was
praised for the performances of its cast.
The film was nominated for three Academy Awards, including Best
Actor for Burton and Best Supporting Actor for Firth.
The two both won Golden Globe Awards for their performances.
The film was also nominated for four BAFTA Awards, with Jenny
Agutter winning for Best Supporting Actress.
The tone is intense and emotional and mind_bending.